# G VIJAYAKUMAR

https://www.linkedin.com/in/gvijayakumar

## SUMMARY

Techno-functional leader with around 20 years of experience including 2 years of working at US location, in Development, DevOps, Web pentesting, experiences in diverse IT products. Have experience working with diverse cultures, & countries. Organizational efficiency with proven track record of providing strategic, technical & operational leadership to increase productivity & production stability in Program Management, IT Delivery, IT Infrastructure Management & Cloud Infrastructure with optimum usage of resources

## **EDUCATION**

• Indian Institute of Management

Executive MBA/Program for Business Managers;

June. 2006 - May. 2007

Email: vijayakumar.gundappa@gmail.com

• Malnad College of Engineering, Mysore University

Master of Computer Applications;

Aug. 1994 - July. 1997

• Mysore University

Post Graduate Diploma in Business Administration;

Jan. 2009 - Dec. 2010

#### CERTIFICATION

a.Scrum Master CSM 2015

b.RHD236 – Red Hat Linux Kernel Internals (RHEL 7.1) 2001

c.MQ System Admin 2005

d. Websphere Admin 2005

e.Oracle certification on "Oracle Enterprise Manager 12c Certified Implementation Specialist" 2016

### Awards

- Received Active Advisor Award 2016, An award given across Fidelity's global locations for proactive advising business users on infrastructure
- Received an Award & a Letter of Appreciation in 2015 from Vice President on successful completion of application migration from AIX & Solaris to Linux.
- Received an Award a Letter of Appreciation in Dec, 2016, for the successful implementation of CAWR(Centralized Automatic Workload Repository) using Oracle Enterprise Manager 12c
- Received an Award & Letter of Appreciation for contributing to the learning initiatives for FMR India as Learning Catalyst in 2010
- Received an Award & Letter of Appreciation from Country head for dedicated & enthusiastic participation in the campus hiring
- Received an Award & Letter of Appreciation for contributing to the learning initiatives for FMR India by being the brand ambassador for culture of coding in 2018

## EXPERIENCE

## • Fidelity Investments

Senior Project Manager

Bangalore, India July 2004 - Present

#### • Bigdata Devops:

Managing, supporting & developing automation for Hadoop big data eco system, mainly developing Enterprise Message/data Bus As A Managed Service using Apache Kafka. The development involves designing, developing cloud based Message Bus PAAS solution using openstack, ansible, node.jS,grafana,prometheus with continuous integration/deployment using git stash, jenkins. This project has saved 1 million dollars in capex and 1.5 million from vendor support as we used pure open source vanilla products. This project has potential to save 20-30% of cost over physical environment, with exponential increase in time to market (from months to minutes)

Calcutta, India

Mobile: +9845445387

Hassan, India

Mysore, India

### o Data engineering team:

Responsible for managing database related projects. An in house application for managing the databases: Database Administration Tool. Oracle Enterprise Manager institutionalization. Reducing the number of duplicate enterprise infrastructure applications by decommissioning legacy ones, saved millions of dollars by optimizing the usage & decommissioning two legacy applications namely Database Administration Tool & Database Enterprise Audit System. Reducing the number of duplicate enterprise infrastructure applications by decommissioning legacy ones, saved 3.5 million dollars by optimizing the usage & decommissioning two legacy applications/teams namely Database Administration Tool (DAT)& Database Enterprise Audit System(DEAudit)

### o Distributed Hosting Application Operations & Engineering, Release engineering:

In this role I was responsible for managing more than 40 member teams, teams consists of

- Middleware teams, the teams that are responsible for managing, engineering, supporting middle products like app servers, web servers, message queuing etc.,
- Release enginerring teams responsible for supporting , managing source code control systems for different business units
- Application support team that supports the Fidelity institutional brokerage applications & Personal, Workplace Investment applications

Saved 3 million dollars by team optimization & infrastructure convergence. Developed UI enabled Application Deployment Tool (ADT) for automated application deployments, have saved 1 million dollars. Saved 10 million by adopting open source products over vendor product in 85% of existing customer instances

## o Onshore coordinator & MW Application support MA & Raleigh, US:

Supporting the PWI(Personal & Workplace Investment) enterprise applications. Planning & executing the production application deployments by working with other enterprise support teams like capacity planning, unix technical support, etc. Saved 5 million thru automation and cost optimization.

### • IBM Software Labs

Bangalore, India Oct 1999 - July 2004

Project Lead

- Autonomic Computing: Developing self managing products. As part of this have developed parsers for different product logs.
- IBM JVM Development: As JPDA component owner, was responsible for architecting, designing & validating the critical line-items that get into the IBM SDK. Implementing new JVM feature enhancements. I helpd with the design, code reviews & committing of the code for JPDA component.
- IBM JVM L3 Support: Providing support to all customers using IBM JVM. Like all Websphere customers